[wind howling]
It is pointless to be afraid.
[Coco gasps]
[EASTHIES]
Once your memories of magic
have taken their leave of you,
so too will your feelings
of fear.
You will be an Outsider
and nothing more.
Why won't you listen to us?
We've told you,
it's not what you think!
Please, no. You can't!
[gasps]
[both gasping, screaming]
What's this?
The Serpent's Bed of Sand?
They're trying to explain
the situation to you!
The least you can do
is hear them out!
Who are they?
Children, sir.
They burned the pennants.
Typical adults.
You say "children,"
as though children are things
instead of human beings.
I hate that.
[EASTHIES] The circumstances
are irrelevant.
The law has been broken.
Peace and order
are vital to the world,
and if we are to maintain
that peace,
witches must honor the law
with strict adherence.
A single crack,
and the wall collapses.
As such,
exceptions cannot be allowed.
[QIFREY]
So very talkative, Easthies,
and so determined not to listen.
Do show my apprentices
some respect, won't you?
Of course.
These girls are your students.
And every bit as insolent
as their master.
[chuckles] If it means
they're unlike you,
then I welcome their insolence.
Especially if this is how
the Knights Moralis operate.
Our desire is only
to preserve order.
To alter the terrain itself,
as occurred in the Dadah Range
or the Shadow Forest
of Thristas...
Such is the power
of the spells of war
used before the pact.
Daring to invoke magic
of this nature
is an act that demands
to be dealt with.
[QIFREY] Don't you want
to find out what happened
before you start
erasing memories?
You should know.
My apprentices
are hardly equipped
for a spell of this scale.
I've not given them the tools
nor the technique.
Presuming you did not,
is it possible
the Brimmed Caps did?
[Qifrey gasps]
[OLRUGGIO] Oi, you two!
Amidst this
rousing debate of yours,
I fear it may have escaped you
what a witch's purpose is.
To spread the blessings
of magic to all.
Ringing any bells for you?
Thankfully, these girls
remember, at least.
So don't just float there.
Make yourselves useful!
Those lovely pennants look like
they could do some good!
[horse neighs]
Thank you.
Is this going to heal him?
No, but it's stopped
the bleeding.
And now I shall take him
to Kalhn.
With a doctor's care,
he may be able to reco--
[DAGDA] I saw you.
You used your magic
to repair your pennants!
Surely it can repair
his wounds, too!
Magic has to be capable
of such things!
[LULUCI]
I'm sorry, but it is not.
[breathes shakily] You lie!
I don't believe you!
[LULUCI] Unhand me.
Now, shall I take the boy
with me or leave him here?
[Dagda cries softly]
[DAGDA] Take him.
And please, keep him safe.
[horse neighs]
[EASTHIES]
Let us seal off the site.
For now, only witches
may be present.
Once the Outsiders are gone...
we'll resume questioning
our witnesses.
[Coco grunts uneasily]
[♪ opening theme song playing]
A basic spell. Unremarkable.
Plainly not the level of power
needed for such destruction.
Indeed not.
Your hands, girl.
[COCO] Huh?
In some cases,
the Brimmed Caps
tattoo their bodies
with grotesque seals.
The seals of forbidden spells,
to alter the physical form
or enhance the power
of their magic.
Hands covered in ink stains,
and a beginner's calluses.
[Easthies exhales softly]
That's quite enough.
[Easthies sighs]
I shall report these events
to the Great Hall
and open a full investigation
in due course.
If your atelier is found
to be the source of the problem,
I'll show no mercy.
I suggest you take care
not to lose
that which you've
only begun to learn.
[Qifrey sighs]
That was a close one,
wasn't it?
I'm glad we all made it
through unscathed.
[Tetia chuckles]
[QIFREY] Perhaps it was unwise
to have split everyone up.
I apologize!
You aren't to blame
for this, Master!
- Everyone showed up just...
- [QIFREY] However, Agott, Coco.
You need to know
that what you did
was extremely dangerous.
If the secrets of magic
had been revealed here today,
every one of the people
we saved
would have had
their memories erased.
Our memories make us
who we are,
and you very nearly
took that away from them.
Sorry, Master.
So am I.
[AGOTT] That's that.
I doubt I'll take that test
any time soon.
But in the end,
you got through it.
Therefore...
I'll make the arrangements
for you
to take the second test, Agott.
[Agott gasps softly]
If you pass,
you will officially be qualified
to accompany me on outside work.
[Agott exclaims]
Can you promise
you won't use magic
in front of people before then?
[AGOTT] Uh?
Yes!
[TETIA] Aw! Only Agott?
Not fair!
What about the rest of us?
I seem to recall that
you three still need to complete
the Basics
of Casting Primer first.
No!
That's fine.
I despise taking tests anyway.
You mean there are
more tests to come?
- [OLRUGGIO] Are you certain?
- [QIFREY] Huh?
As I recall, you feared Agott
was getting ahead of herself.
True.
- [QIFREY] But...
- You can do it, Agott!
[QIFREY]
...this feels different.
And in all fairness,
I believe she's earned
a bit of trust.
[OLRUGGIO] You spoil them.
[QIFREY] How can I not,
when they're always
so hard on themselves?
[OLRUGGIO] Hmm.
[AGOTT] Master Qifrey!
I want to get back
and start practicing!
Not quite yet.
[AGOTT] Uh...
There's one more thing
we still need to do.
[UTOWIN] That girl was
Qifrey's new apprentice, right?
If the rumors
going around are true.
Do you have any evidence
to suggest that they are?
No. Bit hard to recover
anything of note
from a petrified house.
Very well. Then we'll have
to extract a confession.
Look...
That spell dried up the entirety
of the downriver area.
A single fallen rock
can bring down the bank,
divert the river,
and alter
the environment beyond.
Were that to happen,
much of the scenery
would be lost.
Never to be restored.
That girl may well be
such a rock.
She cannot be allowed to fall.
I must pluck her out
delicately.
[Coco exclaims]
[QIFREY]
Olruggio has a special pen.
It's called a Searwire Wand,
and it lets him burn
Casting Seals
into rocks and trees.
[OLRUGGIO]
This should help for now.
[QIFREY]
The river has begun to return.
The effects of the rending spell
must be wearing off!
Hm?
- Coco.
- [COCO] Uh?
[COCO] Huh?
[QIFREY] Here,
you dropped these.
[COCO] Oh.
[QIFREY] Do take care.
Your cap and ink aren't items
you want to leave behind.
[COCO] I'm sorry.
Thank you, Master Qifrey.
Wait, what? That's strange.
[QIFREY] Huh?
[COCO] The vial
is still completely full.
[Coco gasps]
A magic vial
that refills itself?
What an amazing world this is!
[QIFREY] Coco, do you mind
if I take a look at that?
All right.
[Qifrey breathes shakily]
[WITCH] Magic is a falsehood
that makes this world vibrant.
These hands draw
the most beautiful of spells...
Only to be so hideously
stained with ink!
Yet no lie...
can survive close scrutiny.
Hm.
I wonder how long
this ruse can be maintained.
How very curious.
This is the ink you were given
by Nolnoa in Kalhn?
Yes?
[QIFREY] Hm.
[COCO] Uh...
- Wow!
- Olruggio...
the girls should head home.
Could you escort them there?
What? Some other business
to attend to?
- [QIFREY] Well...
- [COCO] Uh...
It occurs to me
that young Coco here
still hasn't obtained her pen.
Kalhn is close,
so we'll make a stop on the way.
Say, could you
pick me up some wine?
One bottle first flush,
one bottle aged!
Aye. That'd be grand.
- I'm sorry.
- [COCO] Huh?
[QIFREY] There's something
I really need to look into.
Hold on, wasn't the door here?
Oh, dear me.
It appears they're closed
for today.
[COCO] What? You mean
the whole shop goes away
when they're not open?
Oh! Hello, Mr. Qifrey.
[Coco gasps]
And you're that girl
from before.
Hello, Tartah!
What good luck.
I need to speak
with Mr. Nolnoa.
Ah, sorry, one moment.
There we are. Go right in.
[Coco gasps]
It's nothing like
last time I was here!
Different doorknobs
lead to different rooms.
What else would you expect?
Granda should be up
on the third floor.
Thank you. Please excuse us.
[TARTAH] Oh, uh...
- Before you go...
- [COCO] Huh?
I don't know your name.
Then I'll tell you!
My name is Coco!
Coco, your leg's
all scratched up,
you really ought to clean it.
[COCO] Oh...
[TARTAH] Come with me.
I can disinfect it
with tranquileaf.
[footsteps]
[COCO]
So many unfamiliar components!
[Coco gasps softly]
Oh, wow!
What are these glittery powders?
Please, just leave it.
I have those
specially arranged.
- [Coco exclaims]
- They're magical dyes.
If you mix them into the ink,
you can alter its effects.
[footsteps]
[QIFREY] Mr. Nolnoa...
Why, Qifrey.
Don't you know
we're closed today?
Yes. Apologies.
Only teasing.
Good to see you.
And I know why you're here.
You're wondering
about the Casting Seal
on those paving tiles,
aren't you?
[Qifrey gasps softly]
[NOLNOA] I still
haven't figured it out yet.
I tried using a spell
to separate out the magic dyes.
But they're blended together
quite thoroughly, I fear.
Have you managed to find
any clues on your end?
Perhaps. I have
something interesting here.
[Nolnoa exclaims] Oh-ho!
Hmm.
It looks very similar!
In fact, I'd say that
faint blue hue is identical!
Qifrey, tell me.
Where on earth did you...
What's going on?
Isn't this one of my vials?
[QIFREY] That day...
The Brimmed Caps must have cast
some kind of spell on the vial.
Qifrey, no!
You shouldn't risk
drawing with that ink
until I analyze it.
Qifrey!
Oh! What's that one
with the color
that looks like aquamarine?
In the big container
hanging from the ceiling!
Right, that would be
azuremoon flower.
Adding it to the ink
makes your spells last longer.
[COCO] And what about
the little sparkly white one,
on the shelf
right across from it?
Blushing bride butterfly scales.
Mixing those in
will turn the ink invisible,
concealing the lines
of the casting seal.
And next to that?
Well, the narrow bottle
is powdered roaming scallop,
and the squat, round one
is powdered golden blaze
wyrm scale.
You're amazing!
You're just amazing, Tartah!
I can't believe you memorized
all those names
and can rattle them off
just like that!
It is our job to sell them.
You're so lucky...
Living in a magic stationer's!
Just look at this room,
at all of these bottles,
and all these shelves!
It's crazy! [exclaims]
Living here must be the best!
[Tartah sighs]
I'd say living in
an atelier's much better.
You say a lot of things
that are strange to hear
from a witch.
I thought you were
an apprentice witch too,
are you not?
[TARTAH] Well, I'm...
[Tartah breathes uneasily]
[COCO] Oh, wow.
That red powder's so bright,
can you tell me what it does?
[TARTAH] Which one?
Up there! On the shelf!
[TARTAH] Hm?
- Right between...
- Hey!
...the rusty brown one
and the aquamarine!
Can you just tell me
where it is on the shelf?
It's the bright red one,
you see it, right?
[Coco gasps]
[bottles rattling]
[TARTAH]
Where'd that light come from?
That was pretty scary!
- You all right?
- [Tartah gasps softly]
None got broken!
That's a relief, isn't it?
- Huh?
- [TARTAH] This is terrible.
A total disaster!
The labels came off.
And they're all mixed up.
Granda told me so clearly
not to touch them,
and now it's a great big mess.
Don't worry!
I'll help you put them back
in their proper places!
Let's start with these.
What are they?
Just tell me which color
goes with which and--
I have no idea!
What? But earlier, you...
I remember them
by their position on the shelf.
I can't tell the colors apart!
[Coco gasps softly]
Please...
Just get out of here.
But I...
[TARTAH] I'm sorry.
I know you want to help,
but I'm afraid you can't.
There are certain things
that certain people
just can't do.
These Silverwash eyes
of mine mean that
no matter how hard I study,
I'll never become a witch.
You can't say I didn't warn you!
Qifrey? You all right there?
[Qifrey grunts]
Qifrey!
For a Casting Seal that small
to have so great an impact...
[Qifrey grunts]
I think we're dealing
with a twinned bottle spell.
Two different vessels,
sharing contents.
There should be a small medal
inscribed with
a Casting Seal in the fluid.
They made Coco use this.
And when she did,
the ink was replaced
with some mysterious substance.
This bottle
is connected to them.
Finally...
I have what I need!
What do you mean?
You're saying that ink
can unleash power like that,
even from small,
scribbled seals?
It can't be!
No, it mustn't be!
This... This is far beyond
my capacity!
I must inform
the Great Hall, of course!
You can't!
It's imperative that this not go
to the Knights Moralis,
nor to the Great Hall.
It's best if no one becomes
aware of what we've discovered.
Why, Qifrey?
What are you suggesting?
You...
Do you truly understand
the implications
of what you're saying?
What is it, then?
What is it you mean to do
with that ink?
Mr. Nolnoa, forgive me.
- [QIFREY] Coco.
- [COCO] Uh?
Sorry for the wait.
Now, about that ink of yours...
It seems he accidentally
gave you
something very expensive.
I bought you a bag
to make up for it. Enjoy.
Oh!
I love it, thank you!
[Coco chuckles]
[♪ closing theme song playing]
Master...
Can you tell me
what "Silverwash" means?
[QIFREY] Silverwash syndrome.
A congenital condition
of the eye
that causes
those who suffer from it
to see the entire world
in silver.
I imagine it would cause
particular difficulty
for witches,
given how crucial
their eyesight is.
And unfortunately,
witches can be
rather unaccommodating
of differences.
Coco.
There's no need
to look so concerned.
You'll be fine.
As long as you're a student
at my atelier,
you'll have me to protect you.
You have nothing
to worry about.
I assure you.
Not a thing.
[TARTAH] Uh?
Granda, I'm sorry.
That light earlier startled me,
and all the jars
got knocked down.
Was that light caused by
a spell or something?
One of Mr. Qifrey's?
[NOLNOA] What, now? A light?
I don't recall any such thing.
Granda?